# MESHIA REED | Software Engineer

I am a Software engineer with 5 years of experience, who fixes a problem you don't know you have in a way that you don't understand. I develop websites for marketing and software development agencies. I'm now looking to bridge my front end developer skills with full stack responsibilities in an environment where technical innovation is vital for business success.

#### Skills

Languages - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, SQL, Mongo, JSON, Typescript, EJS, DTL

Database - PostgreSQL, MongoDB | Other - RESTful Routing, JSON api

Libraries and Frameworks - React (class based and hooks), Express.js, Django, jQuery, Bootstrap

# **Professional Experience**

#### Front End Developer | meltmedia | Tempe, AZ

APRIL 2021 - PRESENT

- Develop 6 websites implementing new color schemes, policies, components, expanding feature functionality, and refactored code for readability using Sass, CSS3, and HTML.
- Build committed software changes using Jenkins to test as well as deploy final versions for production.
- Deliver interactive user experience through clean reusable code, cross browser compatibility, web accessibility, and call to action features increasing time on websites by 37%.
- Discover new software and techniques to maintain clean code for future client services.
- Update training documentation (life cycle guide and 101 guide); led training sessions for 7 new and current employees, ensuring team members are well-rounded developers.

#### Front End Developer | Dansons USA | Phoenix, AZ

APRIL 2019 - MARCH 2021

- Provide clean code interfaces from UI design prototypes for stakeholders, while collaborating with marketing, social media, and the customer service teams, contributing to an 14% increase in incremental revenues within one year.
- Built mobile friendly user interfaces using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap 4, PHP, and Twig.
- Execute new changes on 4 websites creating an interactive user experience through optimization of media files, cross-browser compatibility, and call-to-action events.
- Design dynamic pages to enhance workflow for content specialists in store management systems.

#### Web Content Specialist (Contract) | Ronin Consulting Group | Phoenix, AZ

OCTOBER 2018 - MARCH 2019

- Implement Search Engine Optimization (SEO) industry standards to optimize web page content and metadata (page title, meta descriptions, heading tags, image descriptions) increasing visibility by 27%.
- Identified product inefficiencies and collaborated with sales and marketing teams to improve product details to enhance consumer experience.
- Performed keyword research to identify high-traffic search terms and content opportunities.
- Analyzed web and social media metrics to measure impact of communication strategies using Google Analytics, Boostability, and Trustpilot.

## **SQL Developer** | Ipro Tech | Phoenix, AZ

NOVEMBER 2017 - OCTOBER 2018

- Diagnosed SQL data over 60% of our products for inefficiencies in client databases.
- Scripted SQL queries to resolve issues and provided solutions for clients to improve workflow, as well as file sequence.

• Used in-depth knowledge, stack traces and log files to eliminate index fragmentations as well as check for data corruption on 5 out of 8 products.

#### Junior QA Engineer | Ronin Consulting Group | Phoenix, AZ

DECEMBER 2016 - NOVEMBER 2017

- Diagnosed and resolved unique nonrecurring problems associated with application software and operating systems.
- Aided in reducing required time for manual testing by 9% reduction for new product builds.

## Service Desk Technician | Ronin Consulting Group | Phoenix, AZ

MARCH 2015 - NOVEMBER 2016

• Diagnosed, troubleshot, and maintained application availability by providing technical solutions interacting with proper settings, which resulted in an 86% ticket closure rate.

# **Software Development Projects**

MAY 2018 - PRESENT

Jotit - Task organization application | MongoDB, Express, React.js, Node.js

- Utilized a MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React.js, Node.js) to build a full stack application in 2 days. With full create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations hitting all RESTful API calls.
- Created an application with a mobile-first approach and styled using Styled-Components and CSS3 with grid and flexbox layouts.
- Introduced React animation to enhance user experience when interacting with list items.

True Foodie - Application accepts end user input for menu items | Express, MongoDB, Node.js

- Made RESTful API fetch calls **to** an Express, MongoDB, Node.js backend handling all create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations, and tested all backend routes during development using Postman.
- Used Mongoose to define schemas for MongoDB collections.
- Implemented ES6 tagged template literals with Styled-Components along CSS3 to provide style and flexbox layout

Tic Tac Toe - Online classic board game | JavaScript, CSS3, HTML5

- Leveraged embedded JavaScript, Vanilla JavaScript, CSS3, HTML5, with partials to organize and display the visual aspects
- Wireframed and planned UI design of application using Sketch and created a database of images using Photoshop.
- Utilized Git control during the production of the application with frequent commits until deployment.
- Tested API routes using Postman to ensure functionality during production.
- Implemented JavaScript methods and functions to utilize an Express, MongoDB, and Node.js backend creating a representational state transfer (REST)ful application program interface(API).

## **EDUCATION**

#### **General Assembly** | Remote

AUGUST 2021 - MARCH 2022

### **Software Engineering Immersive**

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, 24-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

**Scottsdale Community College** | Scottsdale, AZ Web Development Certification

OCTOBER 2016 - MAY 2018

Northwestern University | Evanston, IL

JUNE 2007 - JUNE 2011

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Art Theory and Practice